http://www.euromech.org/about/privacy-policy

Privacy policy
This site collects some personal data from its users.
D-52074 Aachen
GERMANY Owner contact email: sara.guttilla@euromech.org Types of Data collected Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects,
by itself or through third parties, there are:
first name; last name; gender; phone number; address; username;
email address; password; fax number; country; county; ZIP/Postal code;
city; Cookies; Usage Data. Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are
provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific
explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection. Personal
Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data,
collected automatically when using this Application. Unless specified
otherwise, all Data requested by this Application is mandatory and
failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Application
to provide its services. In cases where this Application specifically
states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to
communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the
functioning of the Service. Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner. Any
use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Application or by
the owners of third-party services used by this Application serves the
purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to
any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie
Policy, if available. Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained,
published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have
the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner. Mode and place of processing the Data Methods of processing The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent
unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized
destruction of the Data. The Data processing is carried out using
computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures
and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the
Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of
persons in charge, involved with the operation of this Application
(administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or
external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail
carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies)
appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated
list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time. Legal basis of processing The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:
Users have given their consent for one or more specific
purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to
process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing
(“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the
following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the
processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law; provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an
agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations
thereof; processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject; processing is related to a task that is carried out in the
public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the
Owner; processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.
In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific
legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether
the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual
requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract. Place The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any
other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.
Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve
transferring the User's Data to a country other than their own. To find
out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users
can check the section containing details about the processing of
Personal Data. Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data
transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any
international organization governed by public international law or set
up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security
measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.
If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking
the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using
the information provided in the contact section. Retention time Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for. Therefore:
Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance
of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until
such contract has been fully performed. Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s
legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such
purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate
interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of
this
document or by contacting the Owner.
The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer
period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long
as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged
to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so
for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.
Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted.
Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to
rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after
expiration of the retention period. The purposes of processing The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to
provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes:
Registration and authentication and Analytics. Users can find further detailed information about such purposes
of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose
in the respective sections of this document. Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:
AnalyticsThe services contained in this section enable the
Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track
of User behavior. Google Analytics with anonymized IP (Google Ireland Limited) Google Analytics is a web analysis service
provided by Google Ireland Limited (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data
collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare
reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It
works by shortening Users' IP addresses within member states of the
European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the
European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP
address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the US. Personal Data collected:
Cookies; Usage Data. Place of processing: Ireland – Privacy Policy – Opt Out. Privacy Shield participant. Registration and authenticationBy registering or authenticating, Users allow this Application to identify them and give them access to dedicated services. Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide
registration and authentication services. In this case, this Application
will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services,
for registration or identification purposes. Direct registration (this Application) The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to this Application. Personal Data collected:
address; city; country; county; email address;
fax number; first name; gender; last name; password; phone number;
username; ZIP/Postal code.
The rights of Users Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner. In particular, Users have the right to do the following:
Withdraw their consent at any time. Users have the right
to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to
the processing of their Personal Data. Object to processing of their Data. Users have the right
to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried
out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in
the dedicated section below. Access their Data. Users have the right to learn if Data
is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain
aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing
processing. Verify and seek rectification. Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected. Restrict the processing of their Data. Users have the
right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their
Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any
purpose other than storing it. Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner. Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.
Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly
used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have
it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This
provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated
means and that the processing is based on the User's consent, on a
contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations
thereof. Lodge a complaint. Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.
Details about the right to object to processing Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the
exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the
purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may
object to such processing by providing a ground related to their
particular situation to justify the objection. Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be
processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that
processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn,
whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing
purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document. How to exercise these rights Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner
through the contact details provided in this document. These requests
can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as
early as possible and always within one month. Additional information about Data collection and processing Legal action The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner
in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from
improper use of this Application or the related Services. The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. Additional information about User's Personal Data In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy,
this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual
information concerning particular Services or the collection and
processing of Personal Data upon request. System logs and maintenance For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any
third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this
Application (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP
Address) for this purpose. Information not contained in this policy More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal
Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact
information at the beginning of this document. How “Do Not Track” requests are handled This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests. To
determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do
Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies. Changes to this privacy policy The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy
at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page and possibly
within this Application and/or - as far as technically and legally
feasible - sending a notice to Users via any contact information
available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page
often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the
bottom.
Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis
of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the
User, where required.
